Friends, if you are logging in to your CSC ID, then as soon as
we
log in, if it is written on your CSC ID that
user is banded, that is,
friends, my CSC ID is opening,
but friends, if it is written on your CSC ID that
user is banded, that is,
you will see it written in red color
and your dashboard is not opening, then
friends, I am going to tell you
in this video how you have to do the solution of user banded.
So
friends, what do you have to do first?
First of all, friends, you have to
download the CSC banner.
Where do you download the CSC banner
from?  You have to come
to CSC spv.in and friends, you have to
scroll down and friends, from here you will
see the CSC Center banner.  So
friends, in this way
you have to download the banner of CSC.
After this, friends,
after downloading the banner, you have to get it made.
In this, as I will show you by
opening it.
As you can see,
you have to download this CSC banner.  If
your CSC ID has been banned, that is, the
error of band is coming, then your CS will be
created in this way here.  You have to
write the name of the CSC center here.
Logo has to be placed here.  And friends,
after this you have to get it printed on flexi
and put it up at your CSC centre
wherever you run the centre.
Apart from this, friends, you will
write CSC ID here.  We will enter the address here.
Friends, what do you have to do after this
?  You will get it installed in your centre.
After this, you have to call your district manager
and get the
physical verification of your CSC center done.
Before getting the physical verification done,
friends, you have to keep one more thing in mind that you will have to
run your CSC center at your location.
Before this, friends, wherever you were driving, there was no
problem.  But friends, from now on, whatever
location your CSC centre is located at, you will have to
run it there only.  Apart from this, friends,
before doing the verification, you have to
upload your police verification here also.
So before uploading the police verification
you have to call your CSC Bank CSC Manager,
you have to upload the
police verification on your CSC ID.
So let me
also tell you how to upload the police verification.
You have to come to the
site register.c.gov.in.  After this, friends, you have to
click on My Account and
enter your CSC ID here and login with fingerprint.
So I'll log in with fingerprint
and scroll down and click submit.
So after this you have to tick here and
click on capture.  As soon as
you click on capture, whatever morpho or
mantra you run, friends, it starts
billing.  You have to
login through biometric.  So I log
in.  After logging in, you have to
directly click on KYC Update.
After this, scroll down and
upload the police verification document.
And friends, from here you have to select the file
and browse.  And friends, you have to
upload your police verification from here.
Friends,
you can see that the police verification should be between 10 KB to 200 KB.
After this friends, you have to
click on update.  Clicked on update.
You can see the verification
document has been updated successfully.
Friends, what do you have to do after this?
From here we log out.
After this, friends,
you have to call the district manager of your CSC
and friends, he will
take a photo of your CSC center from inside.  They will
take your photo from outside and will physically verify
your CSC centre by making you stand outside with them.
Friends, only then
your CSC ID will be able to be
unlocked as per the user mandate.
So friends, let me
tell you again in this way.  You have to keep three things in
mind.  One thing is that
you have to run your CSC
ID at the CSC location.  The second thing is that
wherever your CSC ID is running, you have to get
proper branding done.
You will be able to use your CSC ID only after branding is done
and the third thing friends is that
after doing all the things, you have to call your CSC
District Manager and get your
physical verification done from him.  Only after this,
friends, the error that you are getting regarding your CSC ID of the banded
user will be resolved.
So friends, that's all in this video.
If you liked the video then do
not forget to like the video and if you have come to the channel for the
first time then subscribe to the channel.  I will
meet you friends
in the next video.  Thank you.